# Omar Hany Front-end Developer

♥ omarhany.com

omarrhanydev in omarhanydev



## **Profile**

Extensive knowledge of front-end development with +4 years of experience, Collaborated with designers and software engineers to translate wireframes and mock-ups into pixel-perfect and interactive user interfaces, Used various desktop, web and mobile frameworks to create applications, Led front-end development of several projects.

# **Professional Experience**

# Izam, inc.

2021 – Present Giza, Egypt Senior Front-end Developer

- Leading the front-end development team.
- Developing multiple modules for **Daftra and Enerpize**, ERP systems to manage businesses using several web technologies.
- Adding new features to WordPress products.
- Applying redesign created by UI/UX designers for Tanqeeb, Jobs search engine in Middle East and North Africa, and Daftra by creating new front-end project using a JavaScript Build tool to bundle CSS and JavaScript files.
- Using various web technologies (jQuery, React, Angular, Vue, Gulp, Webpack) to create webpages and apps.

2019 – 2021 Giza, Egypt Front-end Developer

- Developing multiple modules for **Daftra and Enerpize**, ERP systems to manage businesses using several web technologies.
- Adding new features to WordPress products.

2016 - 2019

**XDev** 

Smart Village, Egypt

Front-end Developer

- Created static web pages and websites and dynamic websites / web applications collaborated with UI/UX designers and software engineers.
- Developed several WordPress websites.

2014 - Present

Freelancer

- Meet with clients and summarize requirements.
- Developed several websites and web applications.
- Developed several WordPress websites.

#### Skills

#### Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP

# Frameworks, Libraries, Preprocessors & Bundlers:

- Front-end Development: jQuery, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Materialize, React, Redux, Angular +4, Vue.js, Gulp, Webpack, Vite
- Mobile App Development: React Native
- Desktop App Development: Electron.js
- Back-end Development: Laravel, Node.js, Express.js

## **WordPress:**

Theme Development, Metaboxes, WooCommerce, Page Templates, CMB2, Custom Post Types, WPML, WPJM

## **Methodologies & Patterns:**

- CSS: BEM, SMACSS, Prefixed SMACSS, OOCSS
- JavaScript: OOP JavaScript, Data Attribute Selectors for JavaScript

## **Template Languages, Tools & Other:**

Laravel Blade, JSX, EJS, Shopify Liquid, Git, Chrome DevTools, Adobe XD, Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

#### **Certificates**

#### React Developer Nanodegree 🗷

React, Redux, React Native.

#### **Education**

2014 - 2017

**Bachelor of Commerce** 

Cairo University

# Languages

**Arabic** Native English

Good

# **Projects**

# **Product Modules and Landing Pages:**

- https://www.daftra.com/ ☑
- https://www.enerpize.com/ ☑
- https://www.tanqeeb.com/ ☑
- https://www.onlineinvoices.com/ ☑

#### **Front-end Development:**

- https://tgdar.vercel.app/ ☑ (In Progress)
- https://justpiece.com/ □
- https://x-dev.tech/ ☑
- https://offeratko.com/ ☑
- https://c-reality-front-end.vercel.app/ ☑
- https://go2globe.x-dev.tech/ ☑
- https://omar-todos.netlify.app/ ☑

## **WordPress Development:**

- https://www.collectiveroutes.org/ ☑
- https://polti-me.com/ ☑
- https://modern-door.com/ □

#### **Desktop Apps:**

https://omarhanydev.github.io/safe-movie-player/ ☑

## **Archived Projects:**

https://github.com/omarhanydev/archived-projects/ ☑